<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Vanilla Factions Expanded - Insectoids</name>
  <author>Oskar Potocki, Kikohi, Sarg Bjornson</author>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <packageId>OskarPotocki.VFE.Insectoid</packageId>
  <description>After a long delay, our brand new Vanilla Factions Expanded module is now ready. Insectoids feature a diversified, new, unplayable faction that will populate the world with insects and monstrosities your colonists never dreamt of. Led by an Ancient Insectoid queen, these eusocial creatures can be heard chittering underground, with outposts and villages across the surface mysteriously disappearing overnight.

Vanilla Factions Expanded - Insectoids allows you to take a fight to the insects. No longer such an interesting faction will be limited to one ingame event only. Insectoids now possess bases on the surface - in the form of overrun outposts filled with riches and hives for you to purge.

They will now be allowed to raid, the same way as mechanoids or other factions can. They won’t engage in diplomacy and they won’t give you quests - as they are forever hostile. This mod features a number of new insectoids filling various niches whilst still keeping the feel of the faction the same as in vanilla - melee only, relying on swarming their opponents.

For those brave enough to harness their power, bio-engineering is now a thing. Obtained from traders and quest rewards only, players can now vat-grow over 20 unique insectoids, obeying their every command and performing tasks around the base.

Genomes used in bio-engineering can also be implanted in colonists and prisoners alike, leading to various genetic mutations - some good, some bad.

New riot gear is craftable and ready to be used by your base security whilst new quest-reward only plasma weapons will allow you to get rid of the insectoids even more effectively.

Mercenaries starting scenario pits you in the battle against the insectoids at the very beginning, placing you on the outskirts of an overrun outpost. Can you clear it out with your superior weaponry and call it home? Or will you evacuate the area and find a new settlement?
  </description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</packageId>
      <displayName>Vanilla Expanded Framework</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2023507013</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>